Jude Juma CV



PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Jude Juma

Date of Birth: 28-4-1991.

Nationality: Kenyan

Languages: English, Kiswahili, Luo

Mobile: +254713751628

E-mail: jude.juma@yahoo.com/judejuma@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/feed/

PROFILE

I am an enterprising young professional interested in continuing my development as a researcher, Information Technology expert and data scientist. I am a result-oriented and I love to work as part of a team. I have a proactive attitude and excellent emotional intelligence.

EDUCATION

2017 May-Present: Bachelor of Information Technology

- Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture & Technology (JKUAT)
- Relevant Courses taken so far:
 - ✓ Computer Application
 - ✓ Computer systems and Organizations
 - ✓ Introduction to Operating System
 - ✓ Introduction to networking
 - ✓ System analysis and design
 - ✓ Introduction to databases management
 - ✓ Introduction to programming (Using C, Java and Python languages)

2011-2015: Bachelor of Science in Laboratory Medicine

- University of Nairobi (UoN)
- Second Class Upper Division
- Relevant Courses: Research methodology, public health, Report writing

2005-2009: Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

• Scored 78/84 points (A-)

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. Oracle Big Data
- Venue: Strathmore University iLabAfrica

• Areas of Focus: Big Data Analytics, Predictive Analytics, Business Intelligence (BI) Big Data Presentation, Machine Learning (AI) Fundamentals of R language and Big Data tools (mining and visualization tools).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1. Kenyatta National Referral Hospital/University of Nairobi Lab

• Laboratory rotations

Rotated for three months every year from 2012 to 2015

(Total of 12 months)

- Assisted hospital physicians in the diagnosis and treatment of illnesses and medical conditions by providing clinical testing and specimen analysis.
- Helped in report writing and record keeping of laboratory research findings.

2. Community Medical Camps

2015 January-2015 March

- Team Leader
- Led a team of students in a qualitative needs-assessment research to find out the health needs of selected slums in Nairobi.
- Roles: Collecting data from the community members, writing reports on the findings of the research.

3. Well Told Story Limited

2016 January-2016 July

- Worked as a research assistant
- Roles: Data collection and Report writing.

4. Samuel Hall

- Enumerator
- Contract ending on 14/11/2017
- Roles: Data collection through interview of questionnaires
- As an enumertaor I interviewed 10 people per day, on average using the KoboCollect software
- Roles: Data collection and Report writing.
- Skills Learned: intercultural communication skills, how to estblish good personal relationship with potetial respondents, lisening skills and good report writing skills.

EXTRA CURRICULUM ACTIVITIES

2011-2015: Chairman, Association of Medical Laboratory Science Students

- Led a team of 6 student leaders
- Organized for student orientation programs and peer counseling programs in campus

2009-2011: Volunteer Work

- Omboga Mixed Secondary School
- Taught Mathematics, Geography and Business studies

SKILLS

Computer Skills

• Microsoft windows 7, 8 & 10, Microsoft Office and Internet Application

Communication skills

- Can communicate fluently in both English and Kiswahili
- Have excellent report writing skills

Counseling skills

- APHIA II Nyanza trained me as a peer counselor in conjunction with the Vintage Consultancy Services and USAID.
- I participated in a training program organized by Engender Health in collaboration with Men as Partners. The training, which took place in 2008, focused on HIV & Gender Based Violence prevention for youths in school.

REFEREES

Dr. Nyagol Joshua Akelo, Senior Lecturer	Caren Namalenya	Mr. Aol Jared
Department of Pathology,	Research Coordinator Well Told Story Limited	Project Coordinator
University of Nairobi.	cnamalenya@gmail.com	Samuel Hall.
Cell phone: +254-711351955 Email: Joshua.nyagol@uonbi.ac.ke	+254726882622	Cell: +254-728981663